SIDDHARTHA PURKAYASTHA

779, Swapnanirh Flat Owner's Association (1st Floor), Road – 2, Nimtoli Road, East Merul Badda, Dhaka – 1212. Mobile: 01712 611966.

E-mail: siduprksto2010@gmail.com



CAREER SAMMARY

About 7 (seven) years working experience in audit and accounts department of various group of companies. Proficient experience of accounts & finance work and related individual risk based audit report of group of companies as per international standards and also experience of tax and vat related rules and regulations.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To secure a responsible position in a leading national or multinational organization requiring innovative challenging employment that will utilize my education, professional skills, experiences in accounts and finance management and other advancement opportunity.

SELF

Hard working, self-motivated, enthusiastic, optimist, competent, working with people and obviously goal oriented.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Company: PARTEX STAR GROUP, Shanta Western Tower, 186 - Bir Uttam Mir Shawkat Road,

Tejgaon I/A, Dhaka-1208.

Designation: Deputy Manager

Department : Internal Control and Compliance, Complex − 1.

Duration : 01 January 2018 – till to date.

Responsibilities: • To prepare and submit the annual audit plan and executing the audit of all business and functional units.

To visit the company's all functional units as assigned by audit action plan

- for identifying operational or process risks and analyzed the audit findings.
 To develop risk based test plan by selecting appropriate audit approach, test procedures and sampling criteria based on professional judgment.
- To prepare working papers of audit findings and review with the audit line Manager.
- To submit the audit report as per agreed action plan and establish the best operating practice for minimizing of risk factors.
- To performed and conduct the compliance related work of companies HR, admin and IT department.

Company: Bangla TV Limited, Bangla TV Bhaban, 83, Siddheswari Road, Ramna, Dhaka–1217,

Bangladesh, +88 02 58313468-69 (PABX)

Designation : Deputy Manager
Department : Accounts & Finance

Duration : 9 months (01 May 2017 – 31st December 2017).

Responsibilities: • To prepare and maintain sales account, sales report for marketing logistics and analytical sales report for the authority.

• To prepare bank book, bank reconciliation, receivable, payable, advance and fixed assets register.

• To prepare and submit the monthly and yearly financial statement of the board of directors.

Maintaining overall Tax and VAT related work in Bangla TV ltd.

Supervision and maintaining overall finance related work.

Company: PARTEX STAR GROUP, Shanta Western Tower, 186 - Bir Uttam Mir Shawkat Road,

Tejgaon I/A, Dhaka-1208.

Designation: Senior Officer

Department : Internal Control and Compliance, Complex − 1.

Duration : 4 years (02 May 2013 – 30 April 2017).

Responsibilities: • To prepare and submit the annual audit plan and executing the audit of all business and functional units.

• To visit the company's all functional units for identified all major risks and analyzed the findings and recommendations and submit the audit report to the management.

• To collect the working papers and evidence document for reviewing the submission of audit report.

• To submit the audit report as per agreed action plan and establish the best operating practice for minimizing of risk factors.

• To performed and conduct the compliance related work of companies HR, admin and IT department.

Company : VIYELLATEX group, 297 Khortoil, Guzipura, Tongi, Gazipur – 1712.

Designation : Executive, Internal Audit.Department : Accounts and Finance.

Duration : 9 months (04-Aug 2012 to 30-April 2013).

Responsibilities: • Inventory audit in all business units and store and also report writing as per applicable rules and regulations.

 Regular bill checking (transport, C&F and local vendors) with relevant document.

 Physical verifications and special investigations for risk minimizing as per management assignment.

• Compliance related work like as maternity, salary and final settlement.

Civil construction work checked and report writing.

Bill of exchange checked in SAP with supporting.

Physical cash counting and submit to audit report.

Stock lot and wastage sale audit.

Company: Masih Muhith Haque & Co. Chartered Accountants, Level # 13, UTC building,

8 Panthapath, Dhaka – 1215.

Designation: Articled student.

Duration : 3 years (02-May - 2009 to 01-May 2012).

Responsibilities:
• Planning, monitoring, reviewing and controlling works of audit and

assurance.

• Preparation of Financial Statements of the various companies, NGOs, Govt.

organization etc.

• Preparation of Management report relating to internal control system and

compliances with applicable laws, rules and regulations.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

 <u>CA-CC</u>: Successfully Chartered Accountancy (CA CC) course has been completed from Masih Muhith Haque & Co., Chartered Accountants under by laws 70, 71 & 74 of the Bangladesh Chartered Accountants Ordinance, 1973 under the Institute of Chartered Accountants of Bangladesh (ICAB). [PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AT A GLANCE]

2. <u>ITP:</u> Successfully completed Income Tax Practitioner (ITP) of under the National Board of Revenue of Bangladesh. Registration No - 06595

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATIONS

Post-Graduation

 Master's in Business Studies (MBS) in Accounting from Modan Mohan College Sylhet under National University secured second class obtained 56.80% marks in 2007.

Graduation

 Bachelor of Commerce (B. Com) honors in Accounting from Modan Mohan College Sylhet under National University secured second class obtained 47% marks in 2006.

Higher Secondary

• H. S. C Commerce group from Modan Mohan College Sylhet under Sylhet Board secured second division obtained 52.50% marks in 2002.

Secondary

• S. S. C Science group from Shiluya High School, Juri under Comilla Board secured first division obtained 61.80% marks in 1999.

LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

Fluency in Bengali over reading, writing, listening and speaking. Good command in English over reading, writing, listing and speaking.

COMPUTER LITERACY

Operating System

• Microsoft Windows 98/2000/2003/2007/XP.

Office Application Software & Internet

Application Software: MS-word, MS-Excel & Microsoft office outlook.

• Accounting Software: SAP, ERP & Tally.

TRAINING SUMMARY

Training Title	Торіс	Institute/ Organization	Trainer	Year	Duration
Microsoft Excel Workshop	Excel 2013: From Novice to professional	Bdjobs.com Ltd.	Mr. Samiul Haq	2016	16 Hours
English Language Courses	English at work	Prothom- alojobs.com	Mr. Mirja Tariq Beg	2013	14 Hours
Psychodrama, Sociometry and Group Psychotherapy	Introduction to Sociodrama and Sociometry: Psychosocial care and empowering disadvantaged persons.	RRTC, Shamoly, Dhaka.	Mr. Herb Propper	2009	10 Hours

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name : Sunil Purkayastha. Mother's Name : Dipu Rani Purkayastha.

Permanent Address : Vill – Bhagadahar, PO – Muraul, PS – Barlekha, Zilla – Moulvibazar.

Date of Birth : May 18, 1983.

Sex : Male.

Nationality : Bangladeshi by birth. Religion : Sonaton (Hindu).

Marital status : Married. Health : Sound.

Hobby : Playing Tabla, reading story books, internet browsing and travelling.

REFERENCE

Mr. Masih Malik Chowdhury, FCA Mr. Gobinda Chandra Das, FCA

Senior partner Senior General Manager
Masih Muhith Haque & Co. Finance and Accounts
Chartered Accountants Partex Star Group

Level # 13, UTC Building, 267, Tejgaon Industrial Area,

8, Panthapath, Dhaka - 1215. Dhaka - 1208.

Tel. # 02-9130675, 9144357. Mob # 01755584988. masih@masihmuhith.com gobinda.das@psgbd.com

CERTIFICATION

I, the undersigned, certify that to the best of my knowledge and behalf this resume correctly describes my qualifications my experience and me. I understand that any willful misstatement described herein may lead to my disqualification or dismissal, if employed.

Siddhartha Purkayastha

wan

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AT A GLANCE

External Audit, Compliance and Accounting Service

SPECIAL AUDIT

Bank & Insurance

- Al-Arafa Islami Bank Ltd.
- Jibon Bima Corporation.
- Green Delta Insurance Ltd.

NGOs/Development

- OXFAM-GB Bangladesh (Various project over the country).
- D'Net Development Ltd.

Corporation/Autonomous body

- Ministry of Local Government & Rural Development (LGSP-Union parishad).
- **ASSETS REVALUATION**
 - Popular Pharmaceuticals (Pvt.) Ltd.

INVENTORY ON FIXED ASSETS

• Berger Paints Bangladesh Ltd.

- Shahjalal Islami Bank Ltd.
- Progoti Insurance Ltd.
- PKSF (Micro credit program over the country).
- PDB consumer audit.
- Appollo Ispat Complex Ltd.
- Beximco Pharmaceuticals Ltd.

ACCOUNTING SERVICE AND MANAGEMENT CONSULTANCY

Garments Industries

- Echotex Ltd.
- Alliance Knit Composite Ltd.
- **Real Estate Company**
 - Diversity Development Ltd.
 - Hilside Apartments Ltd.
- Others
 - North East Medical (Pvt.) Ltd.
 - Aamra Technologies Ltd.
 - Haque Brothers Industries Ltd.

- Asiatic Group.
- Columbia Apparels Ltd.
- Property Business (Pvt.) Ltd.
- Silco Pharmaceuticals Ltd.
- Sylhet Cable System Ltd.
- MGH Group.

Taxation Service

During my CA course, I was involved with the Taxation Department of Masih Muhith Haque & Co. Chartered Accountants where I provided ongoing assistance to the clients and submission of tax return under the self-assessment regime also computation of salary tax.